

# Gabriel Méndez Reyes

Software Engineer

Proactive software engineer focused on the front-end with more than two years of experience in this field. Consider myself a person with strong problem-solving skills that deliver business value through software. Focused and dedicated on best practices, design patterns, and agile methodologies.

✓ gabriel.mendez0@hotmail.com

Santo Domingo, Dominican Republic

gabo-mndz.vercel.app/

### . +1 829-643-2322

19 July, 1998

in linkedin.com/in/gabrielmndz

### **EDUCATION**

## **University Degree**

Technological Institute of Santo Domingo

08/2016 - 04/2020

3.7 GPA

Program

Software Engineering

## Technical High School

Salesian Technical Institute ITESA

08/2012 - 05/2016 3.6 GPA

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Software Developer

Xpert Code / Claro Dominicana

08/2019 - Present Dominican Republic

Outsourcing for Xpert Code company at Claro IT Department

#### Tasks

- Full-Stack in ReactJS and Java Spring technologies.
- CI / CD in Jenkins and Openshift technologies.
- Management of agile SCRUM methodology.

Contact: Daniel Peña - 1829-988-8135

## Mobile Developer

## Caribe Media / Claro Dominicana

03/2018 - 07/2019 Dominican Republic

Outsourcing for Caribe Media company at Claro IT Department

- Front-End in Xamarin Forms and Kotlin technologies.
- Modifying a software application made with Xamarin Forms to fix errors or upgrade user interfaces.
- Create user stories, manage issues, and communicate with the team through Azure DevOps.

Contact: Francis Zorrilla - 1809-350-3756

## **Mobile Developer** Agua Planeta Azul

10/2017 - 02/2018

Dominican Republic

Working at the company IT Department

#### Tasks

- Front-End in the technology of Xamarin Forms.
- Writing and implementing efficient code implementing design pattern.
- Develop new functionalities in the application based on client's requirements.

Contact: Sergio Ceballos - 1 809-444-3777

### **SKILLS**

React Xamarin Forms Kotlin Git

JavaScript TypeScript HTML CSS

RESTful API Oracle Java C#

## **PROJECTS**

Beekeeper (08/2019 - 04/2020) 🗗

- Developed in ReactJS and .NET Core technologies.
- It's a software dedicated to the control of attendance of university students.
- My participation in this project was the front-end development and activities such as the design and implementation of the database.

### **CERTIFICATES**

Kotlin Development by KeepCoding (04/2020) ✓

Big Data Diploma by MESCYT (09/2019 - 12/2019) 
Knowledge related to Big Data in the EOI

Web development with HTML/CSS/JS by MESCYT (08/2019 - 11/2019) ☑

Development of pages with HTML CSS and JQuery

Database Administrator (06/2019)

Web Development with C# Language by MESCYT (10/2018 - 01/2019) ☑

Development of WebForms and MVC pages with .NET

English Immersion Program by MESCYT (01/2017 - 11/2017) ☑

Microsoft Office Specialist Office Power Point (08/2015 - 05/2016) ☑

#### **LANGUAGES**

Spanish
Native or Bilingual Proficiency

English

iciency Professional Working Proficiency

#### **INTERESTS**

Software Development

Front-End Development

UI/UX

**API Services** 

Data Structures

Design Patterns

Agile Methodologies